PERSONAL INFORMATION

Enrique Catalá Bañuls





enrique@enriquecatala.com

www.enriquecatala.com

https://es.linkedin.com/in/enriquecatala



Sex Male | Date of birth 25/04/1981 | Nationality Spanish

BIO

Technical Leader at SolidQ, **Computer Engineer**, <u>Microsoft Data Platform MVP</u> and Microsoft Certified Trainer. I'm passionate on solving performance problems in OLTP systems (database, dotnet and bare metal). Also specialized in the definition and implementation of reliable high availability solutions in Azure and on premises, where I successfully led more than 150 projects not only in Spain but in different countries like USA, United Arab Emirates, Netherlands, Mexico, Saudi Arabia, Austria... I'm the principal architect and coder of the SolidQ solutions called <u>HealthCheck</u>, <u>QueryAnalytics</u> and <u>DatabaseObfuscator</u>. Regular speaker at <u>SolidQ SUMMIT</u>, member and speaker at SQL PASS in Spain and Latin America, staff member of the <u>Madrid's SQLSaturday edition</u>. I'm always trying to help people with both my <u>personal blog</u>, my <u>GitHub account</u> and the SolidQ Blog with my colleagues of SolidQ.

WORK EXPERIENCE

January 2020 - Present

Technical Leader SolidQ (www.solidq.com)

- Be Azure Data Platform evangelist with customers (by participating in public events)
- Be the point of contact with the customers that require advanced knowledge in the Data Platform area.
- Focus on get and maintain the edge of the technical knowledge in Azure and the data platform state, to share with my colleagues and help them achieve better results
- Be part of the engineering team of some of the tools that SolidQ is leveraging internally to improve their services
- Help to achieve the best performance, scalability and security for the solution implemented to my customers
- Define, fine tune and troubleshoot complex scenarios related with DataPlatform, which includes AlwaysOn, replication, Service Broker, Clustering, Kubernetes, Docker,...in both Azure and OnPremises architectures

January 2019 – 2020

Spain Relational Team Leader SolidQ (www.solidq.com)

- Understand my customers to end with the best architecture for their needs
- Create and manage the entire project portfolio with time, milestones, resources
- Help my sales team with successful engagements with customers
- Help my team to achieve the best implementation for the solutions they are working on (in the data platform area)
- Be a reference person when dealing on complex architecture designs/implementation that requires specific skills on the Data Platform area

January 2008 – 2019

Mentor

SolidQ (www.solidq.com)

• Improve the ROI of the customer by improving their architecture

Currículum vítae Enrique Catalá Bañuls

- Design and implementation of highly scalable and reliable OLTP solutions in critical systems (banking, insurance, online payment methods, e-commerce, ...).
- Performance and availability troubleshooting in critical 24x7 systems both at SQL Server level and client application (.NET)
- Design of advanced analytical solutions with machine learning (R and Analysis Services data mining, ...)
- Performance audits of .NET applications (backend mainly)
- Business intelligence projects with tabular technology (PowerBI with DAX)
- Architect and developer of QueryAnalytics and HealthCheck

April 2004 - January

nuary Data analyst 2008 Tabimed S.A.

Tabimed S.A. (now part of www.bancosabadell.com)

 Design and architecture of the data access layers for their core Applications (tasaciones de bienes inmuebles)

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

August 2020 – Present Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals

Expedited by Microsoft

NOTE: For more info, please visit my official MS transcript (id: 977266---code: enriquecatala)

January 2020 – Present

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate

Microsoft Certified: Solutions Associate: SQL 2016 Database Administration

Expedited by Microsoft

NOTE: For more info, please visit my official MS transcript (id: 977266---code: enriquecatala)

2016 - Present

Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert: Data Management and Analytics

Expedited by Microsoft

NOTE: For more info, please visit my official MS transcript (id: 977266---code: enriquecatala)

2015 - 2016

Master en Business Intelligence & Analytics con tecnologías Microsoft

Expedited by SolidQ

<u>Details</u>: Focused on data analysis with R, data mining and scalable data warehousing design for Petabyte solutions.

2013 - Present

Microsoft Certified Trainer

Expedited by Microsoft (yearly renewed since 2013).

NOTE: For more info, please visit my official MS transcript (id: 977266---code: enriquecatala)

2013 - Present

Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert

Expedited by Microsoft

Areas:

- Data Management and Analytics
- Data Platform

NOTE: For more info, please visit my official MS transcript (id: 977266---code: enriquecatala)

2013 - Present Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate

Expedited by Microsoft

NOTE: For more info, please visit my official MS transcript (id: 977266---code: enriquecatala)

2010 - Present Microsoft Certified IT Professional

Expedited by Microsoft

Database Developer and administration

NOTE: For more info, please visit my official MS transcript (id: 977266---code: enriquecatala)

2010 - Present Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist

Expedited by Microsoft

NOTE: For more info, please visit my official MS transcript (id: 977266---code: enriquecatala)

2004 Computer Engineer

Expedited by University of Alicante.

Honors obtained with my final master project called <u>modelado de objetos en almacenes de datos</u> <u>relacionales.</u>

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue

Spanish, Catalonian

Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C1	C2	C1	C1	C2

English

Nivel: A1/A2: usuario básico - B1/B2: usuario independiente - C1/C2: usuario competente Marco común Europeo de referencia para las lenguas

Communication skills

I worked for more than 150 companies and my focus is usually meeting with the CIO to explain how to achieve the best ROI and with the developers to help them built the new architecture. I have good communication skills acquired during my experiences as a national and international speaker in different big events such as Microsoft TechSummit, Codemotion, SQL Pass, dotNetConference... where I have spoken in front of more than 500 people on several occasions. I'm involved in several projects that typically ends with 2h/week meetings with USA customers (English)

Organizational and managerial skills

Leadership. Although at present I have personnel in charge in my company, it is frequent that in all the projects that I carry out, the customer puts me in charge of several of his own employees

Job-related skills

Good capacity for detecting inefficient architectures.

Transmission of knowledge:

• I am used to transmit knowledge to the people who work with me to make the team stronger

Languages commonly used

T-SQL, DAX, C#, python, PowerShell, PowerShell, M, R

Other skills:

- Data Analytics
- Performance tuning
- Azure data Platform
- Data platform migrations to Cloud
- Reliable High availability solutions
- Azure software integration
- Business Intelligence
- Multithread .net coding
- MVVM coding patterns
- Windows Universal Platform
- XAML
- ROI
- WCF

Other competences

Methodical and organized. Because in my current company I am in telecommuting (when I am not displaced to a client), I have acquired good habits of time control and organization

Driver license

A and B

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Microsoft official publications

- Implementación de un sistema de alta disponibilidad multisite con AlwaysON https://msdn.microsoft.com/es-es/sqlserver/dn393901
- Instalación de SQL Server paso a paso https://msdn.microsoft.com/es-es/sqlserver/gg521092
- Instalación de clusters SQL Server paso a paso http://msdn.microsoft.com/es-es/sqlserver/gg601099
- Instalación y configuración de SQL Server Integration Services paso a paso http://msdn.microsoft.com/es-es/sqlserver/gg690203
- Log shipping personalizado http://msdn.microsoft.com/es-es/sqlserver/hh291511
- Framework de administración declarativa http://msdn.microsoft.com/es-es/sqlserver/hh479546

Published books

- Planificando la migración de SQL Server 2000-2005 a SQL Server 2008 R2 (ISBN: 978-84-936417-9-5)
- Summit 2008 Madrid: Relational DB Track (ISBN: 978-84-936417-1-9)
- Planificando la migración de SQL Server 2000-2005 a SQL Server 2008 (ISBN: 978-84-936417-6-4)

Training material created

I'm the author of some international courses offered by my company. Some examples:

- Planes de ejecución con SQL Server
- SQL Server Optimization, Performance Tuning and Troubleshooting
- Administración de SQL Server 2016
- Administración de SQL Server 2014
- ...

Projects

I work for companies under NDA, so I can not disclose the companies I work for. The sectors in which I work, usually are 24x7 open environments with business volumes of hundreds or thousands of millions of euros and rely almost entirely on computer systems.

Banking, insurance, high-risk online payments, car rental and booking of flights, naval management, are some of the sectors in which I usually work.

Speaker in conferences

National and international speaker at numerous events. You can find some of them in my official portfolio. Here some few examples:

- Microsoft TechSummit: <u>Cortana Intelligence Suite: Datawarehouse como servicio en Azure (SQLDW)</u>
- SQL Saturday: Como leer planes de ejecución en SQL Server

Currículum vítae Enrique Catalá Bañuls

- Codemotion:
 - Cómo hacer tuning a capas de acceso a datos .NET
 - Arquitecturas escalables en Azure: Mentiras y verdades

I have a YouTube channel where I'm talking about data engineering: https://youtube.com/enriquecatala

Here at my SlideShare account you can find my last 42 conferences http://www.slideshare.net/enriquecatala

Groups

- Member and co-founder of <u>SQL Saturday Spain</u>
- Member of Professional Association of SQL Server Professionals (PASS)

ATTACHMENTS

- MS_Learning_Transcript.pdf
- ExecutiveRecognitionLetter.pdf